Guide to the William Saroyan Papers, 1926-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1928-1981., Series 5
  - Collections, Subseries 5.07
    - Dear Baby: Titled "Elegie and Salute," first draft TS, corrected,1944 (Carton 83, Folder 14)
    - Dear Baby: Titled "Elegie and Salute," TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 83, Folder 15)
    - Dear Baby: Titled "Elegie and Salute," TS carbon, pp. 146-250,n.d. (Carton 83, Folder 16)
    - Dear Baby: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 83, Folder 17)
    - A Few Malibu Beach Pebbles, 1956: Titled "Penny Papers," TS, corrected; TS carbon, 2 copies,1957 (Carton 83, Folder 18)
    - A Few Malibu Beach Pebbles, 1956: TS carbon, corrected,1957 (Carton 83, Folder 19)
    - A Fine How Do You Do: TS; TS carbon,1939 (Carton 83, Folder 20)
    - 43 Little Plays: TS carbon, corrected; TS carbon, signed (23 plays herein) (Carton 83, Folder 21)
    - 43 Little Plays: Titled "Dialogues," TS carbon, corrected (Carton 83, Folder 22)
    - Gone Today: Titled "You Say You're Not Satisfied," TS carbon, annotated,1962 (Carton 83, Folder 23)
    - Gone Today: Titled "You Say You're Not Satisfied," TS carbon, corrected,1962 (Carton 83, Folder 24)
    - Gone Today: TS carbon, corrected,1963 (Carton 83, Folder 25)
    - Gone Today: TS carbon, corrected,1963 (Carton 83, Folder 26)
    - Gone Today: TS carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 83, Folder 27)
    - Growing Up in America: TS, corrected,1953 (Carton 84, Folder 1)
    - Growing Up in America: TS; TS carbon, corrected; tearsheet,1953 (Carton 84, Folder 2)
    - Growing Up in America: TS carbon,1953 (Carton 84, Folder 3)
    - Growing Up in America: TS carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 84, Folder 4)
    - Growing Up in America: TS carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 84, Folder 5)
    - Growing Up in America: Misc.,1952 (Carton 84, Folder 6)
    - How to Be Human: TS; notes,1936 (Carton 84, Folder 7)
    - How to Be Human: Notes,1941 (Carton 84, Folder 8)
    - How to Be Human: Notes,1941 (Carton 84, Folder 9)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Titled "Misconfessions," TS, corrected; TS carbon,1968 (Carton 84, Folder 10)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Early compilation, TS; TS carbon; tearsheets, mimeos, etc. ,n.d. (Carton 84, Folder 11)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: TS, four additional pieces,n.d. (Carton 84, Folder 12)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Titled "A Lot of Little Old Pieces," TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 84, Folder 13)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Titled "A Lot of Little Old Pieces," setting copy, pp. 1-209,1968 (Carton 84, Folder 14)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Setting copy, pp. 210-426,1968 (Carton 84, Folder 15)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Galleys, corrected,1968 (Carton 84, Folder 16)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Galleys, corrected,1968 (Carton 84, Folder 17)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Galleys, pp. 1-105,1968 (Carton 85, Folder 1)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Galleys, pp. 106-188,1968 (Carton 85, Folder 2)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Galleys, pp. 189-234,1968 (Carton 85, Folder 3)
    - I Used to Believe I Had Forever, Now I'm Not So Sure: Jacket copy,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 4)
    - Little Children: Notes,1936 (Carton 85, Folder 5)
    - Little Microscopic Forms: TS carbon, annotated,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 6)
    - Little Microscopic Forms: TS, corrected,1952 (Carton 85, Folder 7)
    - The Long Way to Tipperary: TS carbon, corrected,1945 (Carton 85, Folder 8)
    - The Long Way to Tipperary: TS; tearsheets,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 9)
    - Making Money, and Nineteen Other Very Short Plays: Titled "Twenty Very Short Plays," TS carbon,1965 (Carton 85, Folder 10)
    - Making Money, and Nineteen Other Very Short Plays: Titled "Twenty Very Short Plays," galleys, 2 sets,1969 (Carton 85, Folder 11)
    - The Man Who Wept: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1957 (Carton 85, Folder 12)
    - The Man Who Wept: TS carbon, 3 copies,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 13)
    - My Country: TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 14)
    - My Kind of Crazy, Wonderful People: Titled "Stories for Drop-outs and Such," galleys, corrected,1966 (Carton 85, Folder 15)
    - My Kind of Crazy, Wonderful People: Galleys,1966 (Carton 85, Folder 16)
    - My Kind of Crazy, Wonderful People: Teacher's manual galleys; booklets,1966 (Carton 85, Folder 17)
    - My Name is Aram: Notes,1939 (Carton 85, Folder 18)
    - My Name is Aram: Misc. notes,1947 (Carton 85, Folder 19)
    - My Name is Aram: Setting copy,1940 (Carton 85, Folder 20)
    - My Name is Aram: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 21)
    - My Name is Aram: Japanese version,1955 (Carton 85, Folder 22)
    - My Name is Aram: Galleys, 1966 revised edition,1966 (Carton 85, Folder 23)
    - My Name is Still Aram: TS, corrected,1963 (Carton 85, Folder 24)
    - My Name is Still Aram: TS carbon, corrected,1963 (Carton 85, Folder 25)
    - My Name is Still Aram: Notes,1963 (Carton 85, Folder 26)
    - A Native American: Notes,1938 (Carton 85, Folder 27)
    - A Number of Ancient and Contemporary Jokes: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1941 (Carton 85, Folder 28)
    - A Number of Fragments: TS carbon, 2 copies; tearsheet,n.d. (Carton 85, Folder 29)
    - A Number of Things Never Forgotten: TS, corrected,1939 (Carton 85, Folder 30)
    - Ohan's Boy; Bepo's Debt; The Killer; Joe's Old Clothes: TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 1)
    - The Old and The New, and Eleven Other Playlets: TS carbon, 2 copies,1959 (Carton 86, Folder 2)
    - The Old Time Religion: 46 pieces, TS, tearsheets, etc.,1945 (Carton 86, Folder 3)
    - Peace, It's Wonderful: Notes,1938 (Carton 86, Folder 4)
    - Peace, It's Wonderful: Notes,1937 (Carton 86, Folder 5)
    - The Playwright and the Public: TS; TS carbon, 2 copies,1959 (Carton 86, Folder 6)
    - Razzle Dazzle: Setting copy, pp. 1-160,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 7)
    - Razzle Dazzle: Setting copy, pp. 161-393,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 8)
    - Razzle Dazzle: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 9)
    - Razzle Dazzle: Notes,1941 (Carton 86, Folder 10)
    - The Saroyan Special: Galleys,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 11)
    - The Saroyan Special: Jacket copy,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 12)
    - The Saroyan Special: Notes,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 13)
    - The Saroyan Special: Misc. front matter, illustrations,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 14)
    - Saroyan's Fables: TS carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 15)
    - Saroyan's Fables: TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 16)
    - Saroyan's Fables: TS, corrected; TS carbon; misc.,1940 (Carton 86, Folder 17)
    - Saroyan's Fables: Holograph photocopies; notes,1941 (Carton 86, Folder 18)
    - Saroyan's Fables: Setting copy,1941 (Carton 86, Folder 19)
    - Saroyan's Fables: Tearsheets,1940 (Carton 86, Folder 20)
    - Saroyan's Fables: Front matter,1941 (Carton 86, Folder 21)
    - Saroyan's Fables: Notes,1941 (Carton 86, Folder 22)
    - Three Plays: TS, corrected; introduction,1940 (Carton 86, Folder 23)
    - Three Times Three: Preface notes,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 24)
    - The Trouble with Tigers: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 86, Folder 25)
    - The Trouble with Tigers: Misc. notes,1938 (Carton 86, Folder 26)
    - The Trouble with Tigers: Annotated folder,1938 (Carton 86, Folder 27)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Titled "Will General Idi Amin Dada be Assassinated? Will Martha Mitchell?" TS; TS carbon,1974 (Carton 86, Folder 28)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Titled "Assassinations," TS, corrected; TS carbon,1978 (Carton 86, Folder 29)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Titled "The Beckett Winos of Gare St. Lazare," TS,1974 (Carton 86, Folder 30)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Titled "Jim, Sam, and Anna," TS,1978 (Carton 86, Folder 31)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Galleys, 2 sets,1978 (Carton 86, Folder 32)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Galleys,1978 (Carton 86, Folder 33)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Page proofs, 2 sets,1979 (Carton 86, Folder 34)
    - Two Short Paris Summertime Plays of 1974: Misc.,1979 (Carton 86, Folder 35)
    - The Whole Voyald: Galleys,1957 (Carton 87, Folder 1)
    - The Whole Voyald: Galleys,1956 (Carton 87, Folder 2)
    - The Whole Voyald: Page proofs,1957 (Carton 87, Folder 3)
    - The Whole Voyald: Misc. front matter,n.d. (Carton 87, Folder 4)
    - The Whole Voyald: Galleys,n.d. (Carton 87, Folder 5)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Page proofs, pp. 1-150,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 6)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Page proofs, pp. 151-250,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 7)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Page proofs, pp. 250-358,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 8)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Page proofs, pp. 360-459,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 9)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Page proofs, pp. 460-498,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 10)
    - The William Saroyan Reader: Publicity,1953 (Carton 87, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, Subseries 5.08
    - The Dumbest Man in the Army (see: Meridian Productions, correspondence) (see: Meridian Productions, correspondence)
    - The Wonderful World of William Saroyan See Omnibus misc. and "The Bad Men" See Omnibus misc. and "The Bad Men"
    - Hairenik Weekly: Reproduction of pieces by WS (Oversize 1)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): Galleys ,1967 (Oversize 1)
    - 1938 (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - The American Lesson: Titled "The People and Things and Places of the Nation," TS, corrected; TS carbon, annotated,1940 (Carton 88, Folder 1)
    - The American Lesson: Radio script,1940 (Carton 88, Folder 2)
    - Around the World with William Saroyan: TS, corrected,1958 (Carton 88, Folder 3)
    - Around the World with William Saroyan: Mimeo TS,1958 (Carton 88, Folder 4)
    - Around the World with William Saroyan: Mimeo TS,1958 (Carton 88, Folder 5)
    - Before the War: TS, corrected,1938 (Carton 88, Folder 6)
    - The Best by Saroyan: TS,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 7)
    - Black Widows: TS, corrected; film idea,1949 (Carton 88, Folder 8)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Introduction TS carbon, 2 copies,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 9)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Christmas in America," TS,1940 (Carton 88, Folder 10)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Christmas in America," notes,1940 (Carton 88, Folder 11)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," mimeo script, corrected,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 12)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," mimeo script, corrected,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 13)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," TS; TS carbon,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 14)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," TS, corrected,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 15)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," TS carbon, 2 copies,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 16)
    - CBS Radio Workshop: Titled "Radio Play," TS; TS carbon,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 17)
    - Come On-a My House: Outline for an Original Screenplay: TS, 3 copies; TS carbon, 2 copies,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 18)
    - Come on Along: All-Colored Revue: Notes,1939 (Carton 88, Folder 19)
    - The Corner Store: TS, corrected, 3 copies,1942 (Carton 88, Folder 20)
    - The Corner Store: Movie production notes,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 21)
    - The Daring Young Man on San Benito Avenue: The Early Life and Times of WS adapted from his writings by Michell Raper: Mimeo TS,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 22)
    - Dear Greta Garbo: From The Collected Short Stories of WS, study guide,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 23)
    - Eternity: A Scenario for a Motion Picture: TS,1933 (Carton 88, Folder 24)
    - Fanny's Family: Story for a Moving Picture: TS, corrected; TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 25)
    - Floydada to Matador, an Interview: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1955 (Carton 88, Folder 26)
    - Floydada to Matador, an Interview: Notes,1955 (Carton 88, Folder 27)
    - For the Record,1955-1956 (Carton 88, Folder 28)
      - "Is This the Cagey Age?," TS carbon, mimeos (2),1955
      - "How About the Awards for Barbers and Bootblacks?," TS carbon, mimeo,1955
      - "The Small Businessman," TS corrected mimeo,1955
      - "Scalawag's Heaven," TS, mimeo,1955
      - "Saroyan Puts U.N. to Work," mimeo,1955
      - "Haphazard Questions," mimeo,1956
    - For the Record,1956-1957 (Carton 88, Folder 29)
      - "A Friendship," TS, mimeo,1956
      - "It's Human to be Stupid Sometimes," TS, mimeo,1956
      - "Prestige or Pay," TS, mimeo,1957
      - "The Cult of Cuteness," TS, mimeo,1957
      - "Saroyan Predicts Nixon as Next President," TS, mimeo,1957
      - "Truth, Nothing But the Truth," TS, mimeo,1957
    - For the Record,1957- (Carton 88, Folder 30)
      - "On Getting Things in Order," TS, mimeo,1957
      - "How Many Sides to the Human Question," TS, mimeo,1958
      - "Intellectuals Gain Recognition," TS, mimeo,1958
      - "The TV Poll Hysteria," TS, mimeo,1958
    - For the Record: Clippings (Carton 88, Folder 31)
    - Gabriela: TS, corrected,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 32)
    - Gabriela: TS, corrected,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 33)
    - Gabriela: TS carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 34)
    - Gabriela: TS, corrected; TS carbon, corrected,1951 (Carton 88, Folder 35)
    - Gabriela: TS carbon, corrected,1956 (Carton 88, Folder 36)
    - Gabriela: Mimeo TS,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 37)
    - Gabriela: Drafts; notes,1951 (Carton 88, Folder 38)
    - Gabriela: Drafts; notes,1951 (Carton 88, Folder 39)
    - Gabriela: Drafts; notes,1951 (Carton 88, Folder 40)
    - Gabriela: Drafts; notes,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 41)
    - Gabriela: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 88, Folder 42)
    - The Grand Prize: Notes,1955 (Carton 88, Folder 43)
    - The Grand Prize: Titled "A Theme in the Life of the Great American Goof," TS, corrected; TS carbon, 2 copies,1939 (Carton 89, Folder 1)
    - The Great Run: MGM script,1942 (Carton 89, Folder 2)
    - Growing Up in Fresno: Radio transcript,1976 (Carton 89, Folder 3)
    - Hey Willie: A Story for Harold Lloyd: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1937 (Carton 89, Folder 4)
    - Husband by Mistake or The Wrong Jim Smith: TS carbon,1936 (Carton 89, Folder 5)
    - Hollywood is Where You Hang Your Head: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1937 (Carton 89, Folder 6)
    - The Human Spirit at Ease: Proposed anthology, TS, 2 copies; TS carbon,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 7)
    - I Call on William Saroyan, by Archie Crashcup: TS, revised; TS carbon; tearsheet,1975 (Carton 89, Folder 8)
    - Invitation to the Dance: Misc. notes,1954 (Carton 89, Folder 9)
    - Jack and the Benny Stalk: Radio script TS carbon; notes,1955 (Carton 89, Folder 10)
    - Joby's Boy: TS,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 11)
    - Joe's Old Clothes: Outline for a Movie: TS,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 12)
    - July 31, 1968: TS photocopy,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 13)
    - Kids: Photos by Aram Saroyan, words by William Saroyan, TS,1968 (Carton 89, Folder 14)
    - The Kiss: TS carbon,1951 (Carton 89, Folder 15)
    - A Letter to Levon Keshishian: TS, corrected,1955 (Carton 89, Folder 16)
    - Life's Dance: Outline for a Ballet-Opera-Play: TS, corrected,1954 (Carton 89, Folder 17)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): Original text, corrected,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 18)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): Photos,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 19)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): TS carbon and photos,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 20)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): TS photocopy, pp. 1-46,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 21)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): TS photocopy, pp. 1-100,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 22)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): TS photocopy, pp. 47-100,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 23)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): Author's first proof,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 24)
    - Look At Us, Let's See, Here We Are, Look Hard, Speak Soft, I See, You See, We All See, Beholder's Eye, Don't Look Now, But Isn't That You (Us? U.S.?): Page proofs; sample page layout; cover,1967 (Carton 89, Folder 25)
    - A Matter of Life and Della: TS, 3 copies; TS carbon,1960 (Carton 89, Folder 26)
    - Merry-Go-Round the World: TS photocopy,n.d. (Carton 89, Folder 27)
    - Moving Up in the World: TS,1966 (Carton 89, Folder 28)
    - Mr. Shaw, Person and Poseur: Lecture TS; notes,1956 (Carton 89, Folder 29)
    - My Son John: TS, corrected,1937 (Carton 89, Folder 30)
    - Omnibus: Misc.,n.d.See also Appendix B for complete listing of Omnibus plays (Carton 89, Folder 31)
    - Omnibus: Misc.,n.d., See also Appendix B for complete listing of Omnibus plays (Carton 89, Folder 32)
    - Performance - I and II: TS, corrected,1932 (Carton 89, Folder 33)
    - The Poetic Situation in America Since Alexander Dumas: TS, corrected, 2 copies,1939 (Carton 89, Folder 34)
    - The Poetic Situation in America Since Alexander Dumas: TS carbon,1939 (Carton 89, Folder 35)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness: Radio script; notes,1939 (Carton 90, Folder 1)
    - The Saroyan Special: Television script,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 2)
    - The Shy Psychiatrist: The Basic Story for a Film for Clark Gable: TS carbon,1948 (Carton 90, Folder 3)
    - Scrivener Saroyan: TS,1956 (Carton 90, Folder 4)
    - So Many Doors: TS; TS carbon,1951 (Carton 90, Folder 5)
    - Society Page Joe: Film script carbon,1936 (Carton 90, Folder 6)
    - A Special Message to the Members of the First Edition Society: TS; galley,1976 (Carton 90, Folder 7)
    - Stories My Grandmother Told Me: Radio script carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 8)
    - Talking Big, Talking Small: TS,1960 (Carton 90, Folder 9)
    - To Load a Boxcar: Film narration TS,1942 (Carton 90, Folder 10)
    - Trapeze Over the Universe: Bound volume, MS, TS, with illustration, in box (Carton 90, Folder 11)
    - The Travelers: TS, corrected,1936 (Carton 90, Folder 12)
    - A Tribute to His Uncle: Mimeo TS, 3 copies; photocopy, 2 copies,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 13)
    - Turn Back the Universe and Give Me Yesterday: TS carbon, corrected; photocopies, 2 copies; tearsheet,1980 (Carton 90, Folder 14)
    - Under the Sun: TS; notes,1955 (Carton 90, Folder 15)
    - Under the Sun: Scripts,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 16)
    - The Wayward Bus: Screenplay script carbon, corrected,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 17)
    - The Wayward Bus: Script mimeo,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 18)
    - The Wayward Bus: TS; notes,1951 (Carton 90, Folder 19)
    - The Wayward Bus: Final shooting script,1957 (Carton 90, Folder 20)
    - The Wayward Bus: Misc.,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 21)
    - What is Painting? A Dialogue on Art by William Saroyan and Manuel Tolegian: TS carbon, pp. 1-125,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 22)
    - What is Painting? A Dialogue on Art by William Saroyan and Manuel Tolegian: TS carbon, pp. 126-227,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 23)
    - What is Painting? A Dialogue on Art by William Saroyan and Manuel Tolegian: TS photocopy,1956 (Carton 90, Folder 24)
    - When in Paris: TS, corrected,1960 (Carton 90, Folder 25)
    - The Woman Who Played With Fire: TS, corrected,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 26)
    - The Working Man: TS; notes,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 27)
    - Ya Yugoslav: TS, 3 copies; film idea,1959 (Carton 90, Folder 28)
    - The Years Ahead: An Original Story For a Moving Picture: TS, corrected,1951 (Carton 90, Folder 29)
    - Untitled: TS carbon; screenplay idea,n.d. (Carton 90, Folder 30)
  - Prefatory Material, Subseries 5.09
    - An Account of the Glorious Struggle of Van-Vasbouragan: Foreword TS carbon,1978 (Carton 91, Folder 1)
    - Arabian Nights: Foreword and jacket copy,1965 (Carton 91, Folder 2)
    - Arabian Nights: Foreword TS, corrected,1965 (Carton 91, Folder 3)
    - Armenian Translation of William Saroyan's Stories: Preface TS carbon,1947 (Carton 91, Folder 4)
    - A Bibliography of William Saroyan: Introduction,1965 (Carton 91, Folder 5)
    - The Bicycle Book: Foreword mimeo and photocopy,1980 (Carton 91, Folder 6)
    - Child's View of San Francisco: Foreword TS carbon,1967 (Carton 91, Folder 7)
    - Choonkoushabadoum: Preface TS carbon, 2 copies,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 8)
    - A Doctor and Literature: Foreword TS photocopy,1964 (Carton 91, Folder 9)
    - Going Crazy: Introduction, TS, corrected,1976 (Carton 91, Folder 10)
    - The Lonely Ones: Foreword TS carbon,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 11)
    - Love Leerics: Foreword,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 12)
    - The Majesty of the Black Woman: Introduction TS, corrected,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 13)
    - Manuel Tolegian: Tolegian on Painting: Foreword TS carbon,1951 (Carton 91, Folder 14)
    - My Name is Aram and Other Stories and Writings: Foreword TS photocopies,1978 (Carton 91, Folder 15)
    - Old America: A Collection of Early Short Stories of America: Preface TS,n.d. (Carton 91, Folder 16)
    - The Paintings of Archie Minasian: Introduction,n.d. (Carton 91, Folder 17)
    - Poems of Nahapet Kuchak: Introduction TS; TS carbon,1978 (Carton 91, Folder 18)
    - The Simple Songs of Khatchik Minasian: Introduction TS, corrected,1946 (Carton 91, Folder 19)
    - Six San Francisco Poets: Introduction TS, corrected,1966 (Carton 91, Folder 20)
    - This Way, Miss: Foreword,1954 (Carton 91, Folder 21)
    - Tomas: Foreword TS carbon, corrected,1969 (Carton 91, Folder 22)
  - Reviews, Subseries 5.10
    - Americans in Paris: TS; TS carbon; tearsheet,1963 (Carton 91, Folder 23)
    - The Best American Short Stories of 1954: TS, corrected,1954 (Carton 91, Folder 24)
    - The Best Plays of 1952-1953: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1953 (Carton 91, Folder 25)
    - The Devil is a Woman: TS carbon,1959 (Carton 91, Folder 26)
    - The Dog's Bark: TS photocopy, corrected,1974 (Carton 91, Folder 27)
    - Down at the Santa Fe Depot: TS, corrected; galley,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 28)
    - E.B. White's Letters: TS; mimeo,1976 (Carton 91, Folder 29)
    - Exiles: TS photocopy, corrected,1970 (Carton 91, Folder 30)
    - Exploring the Child's World: TS carbon,1951 (Carton 91, Folder 31)
    - A Flann O'Brien Reader: TS carbon,1978 (Carton 91, Folder 32)
    - The Flowers of Friendship: TS, corrected,1953 (Carton 91, Folder 33)
    - Lawrence Langer Autobiography: TS,1954 (Carton 91, Folder 34)
    - New Irish Writing: TS, corrected,1976 (Carton 91, Folder 35)
    - Paris Notebook: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1976 (Carton 91, Folder 36)
    - Passage to Ararat: TS, corrected; TS carbon,1975 (Carton 91, Folder 37)
    - Stories and Plays: TS carbon, 2 copies; galley,1976 (Carton 91, Folder 38)
    - The Secret in the Daisy: Fragment, annotated,1955 (Carton 91, Folder 39)
    - Six Nonlectures: Galleys,1954 (Carton 91, Folder 40)
    - Teresa and Other Stories: TS,1947 (Carton 91, Folder 41)
    - Thornton Wilder: An Intimate Portrait: TS, corrected; galley; setting copy,1975 (Carton 91, Folder 42)
    - The Tooth Merchant: TS carbon,1973 (Carton 91, Folder 43)
    - Where the Lilies Bloom: TS,1969 (Carton 91, Folder 44)
    - Who Struck John?: TS carbon,1956 (Carton 91, Folder 45)
  - Poems, Subseries 5.11